{
	"question_set_id": "a34acaa5-d40a-4339-9264-121e74258139",
	"topic_id": "806e2b8d-2d16-4138-abab-507ce429eacf",
	"tags": ["the-aircraft"],
	"title": "The Aircraft",
	"references": [
		{
			"text": "Waypoints Vol 05: PPL/CPL Air Law. Chapter 2: The Aircraft",
			"url": "https://www.waypoints.nz/products/vol-05-ppl-cpl-air-law-january-2017"
		}
	],
	"questions": [
    {
			"question": "What category of airworthiness certificate is required for aircraft used for Air Transport Operations (ATOs)?",
			"answer": "Standard category.",
			"references": [
				{
				  "text": "Waypoints 2-3",
				  "url": ""
				},
				{
					"text": "CAR Part 135 (135.53 - Aircraft airworthiness)",
					"url": "https://www.caa.govt.nz/rules/Rule_Consolidations/Part_135_Consolidation.pdf"
				}
			]
		},
    {
			"question": "Can an aircraft with a restricted category airworthiness certificate be used in an ATO or CTO? If yes, under what condition?",
			"answer": "Yes, only for a CTO. The aircraft flight manual allows such an operation.",
			"references": [
				{
				  "text": "Waypoints 2-3",
				  "url": ""
				},
				{
					"text": "CAR Part 135 (135.53 - Aircraft airworthiness)",
					"url": "https://www.caa.govt.nz/rules/Rule_Consolidations/Part_135_Consolidation.pdf"
				}
			]
		},
    {
			"question": "What are the six category groups within the Special category?",
			"answer": "Special - experimental. Special - exhibition. Special - amateur built. Special - primary. Special - light sport aircraft (LSA). Special - limited.",
			"references": [
				{
				  "text": "Waypoints 2-3",
				  "url": ""
				},
				{
					"text": "CAR Part 21 (21.173 - Certificate categories)",
					"url": "https://www.caa.govt.nz/rules/Rule_Consolidations/Part_021_Consolidation.pdf"
				}
			]
		},
    {
			"question": "A flight test called an __________ __________ __________ may be required after maintenance that may have appreciably affected the flight characteristics or operation of the aircraft.",
			"answer": "Operational flight check.",
			"references": [
				{
				  "text": "Waypoints 2-4",
				  "url": ""
				},
				{
					"text": "CAR Part 43 (43.103(4) - Requirements for certifying release-to-service)",
					"url": "https://www.caa.govt.nz/rules/Rule_Consolidations/Part_043_Consolidation.pdf"
				}
			]
		},
    {
			"question": "Aircaft issued with a special category airworthiness certificate require a legible __________ with wording the same as or similar to wording in CAR 21.205.",
			"answer": "Placard",
			"references": [
				{
				  "text": "Waypoints 2-4",
				  "url": ""
				},
				{
					"text": "CAR Part 21 (21.205 - Placard for special category aircraft.",
					"url": "https://www.caa.govt.nz/rules/Rule_Consolidations/Part_021_Consolidation.pdf"
				}
			]
		},
    {
			"question": "When might a provisional airworthiness certificate be issued?",
			"answer": "When the applicant has applied for a type certificate (or supplemental type certificate).",
			"references": [
				{
				  "text": "Waypoints 2-4",
				  "url": ""
				},
				{
					"text": "CAR Part 21 (21.145(a)(1) - Issue of certificate)",
					"url": "https://www.caa.govt.nz/rules/Rule_Consolidations/Part_021_Consolidation.pdf"
				}
			]
		},
    {
			"question": "When can an aircraft have airworthiness certificates in multiple categories, and which categories are these?",
			"answer": "When the aircraft can be converted from one configuration to another by removing or adding equipment by simple mechanical means. Standard and restricted categories..",
			"references": [
				{
				  "text": "Waypoints 2-4",
				  "url": ""
				},
				{
					"text": "CAR Part 21 (21.177 - Special conditions for issue of certificate)",
					"url": "https://www.caa.govt.nz/rules/Rule_Consolidations/Part_021_Consolidation.pdf"
				}
			]
		},
    {
			"question": "If an aircaft with a standard, restricted, special, or provisional certificate is sold, the certificate (is/is not) transferred with the aircraft.",
			"answer": "Is.",
			"references": [
				{
				  "text": "Waypoints 2-4",
				  "url": ""
				},
				{
					"text": "CAR Part 21 (21.181 - Transfer of certificate)",
					"url": "https://www.caa.govt.nz/rules/Rule_Consolidations/Part_021_Consolidation.pdf"
				}
			]
		},
    {
			"question": "An airworthiness certificate remains in force unless the certificate __________, is __________ or __________, provided that __________ is performed in accordance with the requirements of Part 91 and 43.",
			"answer": "Expires. Suspended. Revoked. Maintenance.",
			"references": [
				{
				  "text": "Waypoints 2-4",
				  "url": ""
				},
				{
					"text": "CAR Part 21 (21.179 - Duration of certificate)",
					"url": "https://www.caa.govt.nz/rules/Rule_Consolidations/Part_021_Consolidation.pdf"
				}
			]
		},
    {
			"question": "Even if the airworthiness certificate is valid, an aircraft shouldn't be operated unless it is in an __________ condition.",
			"answer": "Airworthy.",
			"references": [
				{
				  "text": "Waypoints 2-4",
				  "url": ""
				}
			]
		},
    {
			"question": "A __________ __________ may be issued for a Class II (2-seat) microlight aircraft.",
			"answer": "Flight permit.",
			"references": [
				{
				  "text": "Waypoints 2-4",
				  "url": ""
				},
				{
					"text": "CAR Part 103 (103.203 - Requirement for flight permit)",
					"url": "https://www.caa.govt.nz/rules/Rule_Consolidations/Part_103_Consolidation.pdf"
				}
			]
		},
    {
			"question": "The __________ __________ is generally written by the constructor of the aircraft, and contains operational information and recommended handling techniques.",
			"answer": "Flight manual.",
			"references": [
				{
				  "text": "Waypoints 2-4",
				  "url": ""
				}
			]
		}
	]
}
